[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the 12th episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
In this case, the Fragment Shader
It's called Useful Sites & Tools.
A site that may be useful for your work or study.
I'd like to introduce you to
All the links are in the overview section.
If you like what you see, check it out!
The first one is called Write a GLSL TOP
This is a page from Derivative, the company that makes TouchDesigner.
If you're using TouchDesigner.
I think we're going to see this place a lot.
It's just like the title says, it's the way GLSL TOP is written and
It contains information on the built-in functions and so on.
For example, if there is a function with a TD and you are not familiar with it, you can use
It's possible that you can see it here
For example, SimplexNoise's
Some functions TD already has built-in, so you can use
I was wondering what kind of functions are available.
I think it's worth a look.
Converting from rgb to hsv
And so on.
The next one is called "Introduction to Visual and Audio Processing
This is the material for Ryo Higa's lecture
This one is more of a GLSL.
It's an explanation of TouchDesigner itself.
It's very well put together.
I think you'll learn quite a bit.
I used to do some workshops privately.
I found it quite helpful.
Please check it out!
Next up, this is the OpenGL
It's what's called a cheat sheet.
If there's a function here that I don't understand that GLSL or something like that.
You can search by that name to find out how to use it and more!
For example, do a search for fract or something like that.
It gets pretty small, so if you zoom in on it
It's around here, like.
It's like this.
The next one is docs.GL, which is also here.
It's something that can be used in the same way.
For example, you could do the same search for fract.
It's going to come out how to use it.
Which one is easier to use than that cheat sheet I mentioned earlier?
I think you can use whichever one you like.
Next.
It's called the OpenGL4 Shading Language Cookbook
I probably read this one or two years ago.
I think it's an edition.
It's also available in Japanese.
I think the edition may be a little outdated.
Then there's the next one, which I've mentioned in the video.
It's called The Book of Shaders.
It's very well explained.
It's a great learning experience because it comes with an editor that you can run on the fly.
So let's take a look at it.
He explained it in detail.
And an editor that actually reflects the code on the fly.
It's all over the place.
I think you'll learn a lot.
Once you've mastered everything here.
I think the range of expression will expand considerably.
Japanese version is also available
It's translated so well in Japanese that it looks amazing.
Check it out.
The next one is called KodeLife.
This is the GLSL desktop editor.
I think it could be used for live coding and other such applications.
You can download it from this page
There are some videos on how to use it, so you might want to check it out.
For this KodeLife.
Mr. Keijiro Takahashi has given many samples.
I think this area would be very helpful as well.
For example
If you copy and paste this code into
It's supposed to work like this.
I think some of the code needs a bit of a fix to get it working.
I can see the behavior like this.
I think you'll learn a lot.
Then the ISF.
I have previously introduced a study method using the ISF.
You can create effects for a VJ software called VDMX
Shader editor.
I have samples of various effects.
I think this would be very helpful too.
For example
There's all kinds of stuff in here.
I have a sample of the effects.
This one has this controller on it.
You can actually move it around.
On the left side, there's a cord that says.
It's supposed to be a way to see what's going on.
This is a bit of an aside, but I made this one a long time ago.
It's what we call a serial drama.
There are parameters.
We're going to increase this place.
It's like having more and more Doraemon in your life
Sometimes it's the opposite with Mirror.
It's got a lot of effects.
It's like this.
I thought it was long gone with the change of domain.
I had some left over, so I thought I'd introduce you to them.
I have the code here.
Take a look if you're interested.
Continue to tweet and tweet the hashtag GLSL on Twitter.
I'm sure some of you may have seen it.
The idea is to write a GLSL at a length that fits in a tweet
A lot of them are of a high standard.
Some of them have sounds attached to them.
Maybe it's not quite for beginners.
I think you'll learn a lot from watching it.
This one, sir.
I'm an editor for that tweet GLSL.
As it's reacting now with the mouse.
This editor also allows for interactive editing and
You can convert to video from here or
You can also post to Twitter
Then there's this WebGL headquarters.
This is the site of h_doxas, who created the tweet GLSL I mentioned earlier.
Getting Started with GLSL Creative Coding with twigl.app
In a series called
He explains GLSL coding in a pretty straightforward manner, so I'm not going to get into the
I think it would be very helpful.
I've been working on this video as well.
There are quite a few things I've been referring to.
I think you'll learn a great deal.
Next, here's a site called ShaderToy.
There's a lot of work up there that's at a ridiculous level.
It's a very nice site.
Of course, you can also submit your work here
For example, if you click
There's a player over here.
It's supposed to have an editor over here.
I've been looking at TouchDesigner related GLSL questions.
How to convert this ShaderToy to TouchDesigner?
I get a lot of questions like.
It's kind of too advanced.
There's an awful lot of potential for me to just copy and paste.
[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the 12th edition of GLSL in TouchDesigner
please help me
In this case, the Fragment Shader
It's called Useful Sites & Tools.
A site that may be useful for your work or study.
I'd like to introduce you to
All the links are in the overview section.
If you like what you see, check it out!
The first one is called Write a GLSL TOP
This is a page from Derivative, the company that makes TouchDesigner.
If you're using TouchDesigner.
I think we're going to see this place a lot.
It's just like the title says, it's the way GLSL TOP is written and
It contains information on the built-in functions and so on.
For example, if there is a function with a TD and you are not familiar with it, you can use
It's possible that you can see it here
For example, SimplexNoise's
Some functions TD already has built-in, so you can use
I was wondering what kind of functions are available.
I think it's worth a look.
Converting from rgb to hsv
And so on.
The next one is called "Introduction to Visual and Audio Processing
This is the material for Ryo Higa's lecture
This one is more of a GLSL.
It's an explanation of TouchDesigner itself.
It's very well put together.
I think you'll learn quite a bit.
I used to do some workshops privately.
I found it quite helpful.
Please check it out!
Next up, this is the OpenGL
It's what's called a cheat sheet.
If there's a function here that I don't understand that GLSL or something like that.
You can search by that name to find out how to use it and more!
For example, do a search for fract or something like that.
It gets pretty small, so if you zoom in on it
It's around here, like.
It's like this.
The next one is docs.GL, which is also here.
It's something that can be used in the same way.
For example, you could do the same search for fract.
It's going to come out how to use it.
Which one is easier to use than that cheat sheet I mentioned earlier?
I think you can use whichever one you like.
Next.
It's called the OpenGL4 Shading Language Cookbook
I probably read this one or two years ago.
I think it's an edition.
It's also available in Japanese.
I think the edition may be a little outdated.
Then there's the next one, which I've mentioned in the video.
It's called The Book of Shaders.
It's very well explained.
It's a great learning experience because it comes with an editor that you can run on the fly.
So let's take a look at it.
He explained it in detail.
And an editor that actually reflects the code on the fly.
It's all over the place.
I think you'll learn a lot.
Once you've mastered everything here.
I think the range of expression will expand considerably.
Japanese version is also available
It's translated so well in Japanese that it looks amazing.
Check it out.
The next one is called KodeLife.
This is the GLSL desktop editor.
I think it could be used for live coding and other such applications.
You can download it from this page
There are some videos on how to use it, so you might want to check it out.
For this KodeLife.
Mr. Keijiro Takahashi has given many samples.
I think this area would be very helpful as well.
For example
If you copy and paste this code into
It's supposed to work like this.
I think some of the code needs a bit of a fix to get it working.
I can see the behavior like this.
I think you'll learn a lot.
Then the ISF.
I have previously introduced a study method using the ISF.
You can create effects for a VJ software called VDMX
Shader editor.
I have samples of various effects.
I think this would be very helpful too.
For example
There's all kinds of stuff in here.
I have a sample of the effects.
This one has this controller on it.
You can actually move it around.
On the left side, there's a cord that says.
It's supposed to be a way to see what's going on.
This is a bit of an aside, but I made this one a long time ago.
It's what we call a serial drama.
There are parameters.
We're going to increase this place.
It's like having more and more Doraemon in your life
Sometimes it's the opposite with Mirror.
It's got a lot of effects.
It's like this.
I thought it was long gone with the change of domain.
I had some left over, so I thought I'd introduce you to them.
I have the code here.
Take a look if you're interested.
Continue to tweet and tweet the hashtag GLSL on Twitter.
I'm sure some of you may have seen it.
The idea is to write a GLSL at a length that fits in a tweet
A lot of them are of a high standard.
Some of them have sounds attached to them.
Maybe it's not quite for beginners.
I think you'll learn a lot from watching it.
This one, sir.
I'm an editor for that tweet GLSL.
As it's reacting now with the mouse.
This editor also allows for interactive editing and
You can convert to video from here or
You can also post to Twitter
Then there's this WebGL headquarters.
This is the site of h_doxas, who created the tweet GLSL I mentioned earlier.
Getting Started with GLSL Creative Coding with twigl.app
In a series called
He explains GLSL coding in a pretty straightforward manner, so I'm not going to get into the
I think it would be very helpful.
I've been working on this video as well.
There are quite a few things I've been referring to.
I think you'll learn a great deal.
Next, here's a site called ShaderToy.
There's a lot of work up there that's at a ridiculous level.
It's a very nice site.
Of course, you can also submit your work here
For example, if you click
There's a player over here.
It's supposed to have an editor over here.
I've been looking at TouchDesigner related GLSL questions.
How to convert this ShaderToy to TouchDesigner?
I get a lot of questions like.
It's kind of too advanced.
There's an awful lot of potential for me to just copy and paste.
Honestly, while you're a beginner.
I don't think you're going to learn much.
So it's not so much for study.
I'll present it to you this time as an ornamental.
Finally, I'd like to introduce you to a website called GLSL Sandbox
Same here.
As you can see by clicking here.
I see this is a site with an online editor.
The code fix is.
It's supposed to change this in the background.
This is the site, but I'm not even logging in anymore, and I'm just going to keep going.
I can post anything I want.
It's a direct copy of ShaderToy or
It's a site that's really noisy anyway.
It's like a nice thing sometimes.
It's a little hard to find, so if you have a really great time, that is.
I think you'll find something of interest, too.
That's it.
Actually, this is the first time.
This is the last episode of the first season.
I'll study and come back to it.
We look forward to seeing you at the start of the second season!
About twice a month at TDSW.
We're running live streaming workshops on the weekend.
Tickets are available through Petix and Eventbrite!
We also use Patreon
There are currently three plans available
You can find these links in the video overview section of the video
Check it out if you'd like.
So thank you for watching.
If you like it, Good Button and
Please subscribe to our channel!
goodbye
[Music]